O.k.
so we're throwing a corked bottle today and the first step of throwing a corked bottle, here's our cork here.
The first step is to center the clay.
Now what I like to do first is get some water on my piece of clay.
This makes the hands slide over it nice and easily like that.
The next thing I like to do is simply push the clay down on to the bat just to make sure I have it nice and secure on there.
You certainly don't want this piece of clay moving around.
So I just push down with this hand, hold it in place with this and simply push it down on to the bat.
I'm now just going to take one of these rib tools we talked about earlier, with a right angled edge, and I'm just going to trim any excess off the base of the centered lump of clay.
O.k., so now we have the lump of clay centered.
The next part of the process in throwing our corked bottle is going to be entering the clay and opening the pot.
And we're going to do that in the next segment.